<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A description of the king and queene of fayries, their habit, fare, their abode, pompe, and state Beeing very delightfull to the sense, and full of mirth.</title>
            <author>R. S., fl. 1635.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1635</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 10 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 12 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A11252</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 21513</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S112131</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99847389</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99847389</idno>
            <idno type="VID">12422</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A11252)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 12422)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1583:03)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A description of the king and queene of fayries, their habit, fare, their abode, pompe, and state Beeing very delightfull to the sense, and full of mirth.</title>
                  <author>R. S., fl. 1635.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6], 1-3, [3], 4, 6, [7] p. : ill.  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed [by T. Harper] for Richard Harper, and are to be sold at his shop, at the Hospitall gate,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1635.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>To the reader signed: R.S.</note>
                  <note>Printer's name from STC.</note>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A¹²  (-A1, blank?).</note>
                  <note>Imperfect; cropped with some loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Fairy poetry, English --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A DESCRIPTION Of the King and Queene of <hi>Fayries,</hi> their habit, fare, their abode, pompe, and ſtate.</p>
            <p>Beeing very delightfull to the ſenſe, and full of mirth.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>depiction of King Charles I and his Queen Consort, Henrietta Maria</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>LONDON, Printed for <hi>Richard Harper,</hi> and are to be ſold at his ſhop, at the Hoſpitall gate. 1635.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:2"/>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:2"/>
            <head>To the Reader.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Courteous Reader,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg> Preſent thee here with the Deſcrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the King of the <hi>Fayries,</hi> of his Attendants, Apparel, Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſture, and Victuals, which though comprehended in the brevity of ſo ſhort a volume,
<pb facs="tcp:12422:3"/>
yet as the Proverbe truely a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verres, it hath as mellifluous and pleaſing diſcourſe, as that whoſe amplitude containes the fulneſſe of a bigger com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition<hi>:</hi> yet not ſo much pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuming on the contentment that it will bring to thee, as partly relying upon thy con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nivence at the faults therein contained, which beeing in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nocent and harmeleſſe, can give no great diſturbance to thy patience, but pleaſe thy palate with varietie of mirth,
<pb facs="tcp:12422:3"/>
and not doubting but my la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour will bee remunerable with your good approbation, I ſhall thinke my paines well taken, and my ſelfe really ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfied with your content<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, emboldning me to ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe my ſelfe</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Yours hereafter, If now approved on, <hi>R. S</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="illustration">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:6"/>
            <p>
               <figure/>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:6"/>
            <l>DEepe skild Geographers, whoſe art a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> s<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Do traverſe all the world, and with their <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Declare the ſtrangenes of each ſeverall clim<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>The nature, ſcituation, and the time</l>
            <l>Of being inhabited, yet all their art</l>
            <l>And deepe informed skill could not imp<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>In what ſet climate of this Orbe or Ile,</l>
            <l>The king of Fayries kept, whoſe honor'd ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                  <desc>…</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Is here incloſ'd, with the ſincere deſcript<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Of his abode, his nature, and the region</l>
            <l>In which he rules: reade, and thou ſhalt fin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Delightfull mirth, fit to content thy min<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>May the contents thereof thy palate ſute,</l>
            <l>With its mellifluous and pleaſing fruit:</l>
            <l>For nought can more be ſweetn'd to my mi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Than that this Pamphlet thy contentm<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> fin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Which if it ſhall, my labour is ſuffic'd,</l>
            <l>In being by your liking highly priz'd.</l>
            <closer>
               <signed>Yours to his power, R. S.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:4"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:12422:4"/>
            <head>A Deſcription of the King of <hi>Fayries</hi> Clothes, brought to him on New-yeares day in the morning, 1626. by his Queenes Chamber-maids.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Irſt a Cobweb-ſhirt, more thinn</l>
               <l>Than ever Spider ſince cou<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> ſpin.</l>
               <l>Chang'd to the whiteneſſe of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſnow,</l>
               <l>By the ſtormie windes that blow</l>
               <l>In the vaſt and frozen ayre,</l>
               <l>No ſhirt half ſo fine, ſo fayre.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>A rich Waſtcoat they did bring,</l>
               <l>Made of the Trout-flies gilded wing;</l>
               <l>
                  <pb n="2" facs="tcp:12422:5"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>t which his Elveſhip gan to fret,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>wearing it would make him ſweat</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ven with it weight: he néede would weare</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> waſcoat made of downy haire,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ew ſhaven of an Eunuchs chin,</l>
               <l>That pleaſ'd him well, t'was wondrous thin.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The out-ſide of his doublet was</l>
               <l>Made of the foure leav'd true lov'd graſſe,</l>
               <l>Chang'd into ſo fine a gloſſe,</l>
               <l>With the oyle of Criſpie moſſe:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>t made a Rainbow in the night</l>
               <l>Which gave a luſtre paſſing light.</l>
               <l>On every ſeame there was a lace</l>
               <l>Drawne by the unctious Snails ſlow pace.</l>
               <l>To which the fin'ſt pur'ſt ſilver thréed</l>
               <l>Compar'd, did looke like dull pale lead.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>His bréeches of the Fléece was wrought,</l>
               <l>Which from Chlochos <hi>Iaſon</hi> brought:</l>
               <l>Spun into ſo fine a yarne,</l>
               <l>No mortall wight might it diſcerne.</l>
               <l>Weav'd by <hi>Arachne</hi> on her loome,</l>
               <l>Iuſt before ſhe had her doome.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>A rich Mantle he did weare,</l>
               <l>Made of Tinſell Goſameare.</l>
               <l>
                  <pb n="3" facs="tcp:12422:5"/>
Beflowred over with a few</l>
               <l>Diamond ſtars of morning dew:</l>
               <l>Dy'd Crimſon in a maydens bluſh,</l>
               <l>Lin'd with humble Bées ſoft pluſh.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>His Cap was all of Ladies love,</l>
               <l>So wondrous light, that it did move,</l>
               <l>If any humming gnat or flie</l>
               <l>Buzz'd the ayre in paſſing by.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>About his necke a wreath of pearle</l>
               <l>Dropt from the eyes of ſome poore girle.</l>
               <l>Pinched, becauſe ſhe had forgot</l>
               <l>To leave cleane water in the pot.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:7"/>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:12422:7"/>
            <head>A Deſcription of his Dyet.</head>
            <l>NOw they the Elves within a trice,</l>
            <l>Prepar'd a feaſt leſſe great than nice.</l>
            <l>Where you may imagine firſt,</l>
            <l>The Elves prepare to quench his thirſt,</l>
            <l>In pure ſeed Pearle of Infant dew</l>
            <l>Brought and ſwéetned with a blew</l>
            <l>And pregnant Violet; which done,</l>
            <l>His killing eies begin to runne</l>
            <l>Quite ore the table, where hée ſpyes</l>
            <l>The hornes of water'd Butter-flies.</l>
            <l>Of which he eats, but with a little</l>
            <l>Neat coole allay of Cuckows ſpittle.</l>
            <l>Next this the red cap worme thats ſhut</l>
            <l>Within the concave of a nut.</l>
            <l>Moles eyes he taſtes, then Adders eares;</l>
            <l>To theſe for ſauce the ſlaine ſtagges teares</l>
            <l>A bloted earewig, and the pith</l>
            <l>Of ſugred ruſh he glads him with.</l>
            <l>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:12422:8"/>
Then he takes a little Mothe,</l>
            <l>Late fatted in a ſcarlet cloth,</l>
            <l>A Spinners ham, the beards of mice,</l>
            <l>Nits carbonado'd, a device</l>
            <l>Before unknowne; the blood of fleas</l>
            <l>Which gave his Elveſhips ſtomacke eaſe.</l>
            <l>The unctious dew tops of a Snaile,</l>
            <l>The broake heart of a Nightingale,</l>
            <l>Orecome in muſicke, with the ſagge</l>
            <l>And well beſtrowted Bées ſwéet bagge.</l>
            <l>Conſerves of Atomes, and the mites,</l>
            <l>The ſtike wormes ſperme, and the delights</l>
            <l>Of all that ever yet hath bleſt</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ayrie <hi>land: ſo ends his feaſt.</hi>
            </l>
            <stage>
               <pb facs="tcp:12422:8"/>
               <hi>Orpheus.</hi>
Thrice exc<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>lling, for the finiſhment of this Feaſt, thou muſt muſicke it ſo, that the Die<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties may deſcend to grace it.</stage>
         </div>
         <div type="illustration">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:9"/>
            <p>
               <figure/>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="song">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:9"/>
            <head>THE FAIRIES FEGARIES. <hi>OR,</hi>
            </head>
            <argument>
               <lg>
                  <l>Singing and dancing b<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ing all their pleaſure,</l>
                  <l>Theyle pleaſe you m<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſt nicely, if y<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ule be at leaſure,</l>
                  <l>To heare their ſweet chanting, it will you delight,</l>
                  <l>To cure melancholly at morning and night.</l>
               </lg>
            </argument>
            <opener>Sung like to the Spaniſh Gypſie.</opener>
            <lg>
               <l>COme follow, follow me,</l>
               <l>You Fairie Elves that be:</l>
               <l>And circle round this greene,</l>
               <l>Come follow me your Quéene.</l>
               <l>Hand in hand lets dance a round,</l>
               <l>For this place is Fayrie ground.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>When Mortals are at reſt.</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:12422:10"/>
And ſnorting in their neſt,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nheard, or uneſpy'd,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hrough key-holes we do glide:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ver tables, ſtooles, and ſhelves,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e trip it with our Fairie Elves.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd if the houſe be foule,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>r platter, diſh, or bowle,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>p ſtaires we nimbly créepe,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd finde the Sluts aſleepe:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hen we pinch their armes and thighes,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>one eſcapes, nor none eſpies.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ut if the houſe be ſwept,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>d from uncleanneſſe kept,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e praiſe the houſe and maid,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd ſurely ſhe is paid:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>or we do uſe before we go</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>o drop a Teſter in her ſhoe.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>pon the muſhroomes head,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ur table cloth we ſpread,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> graine o'th fineſt wheat</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s manchet that we eate:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he pearlie drops of dew we drinke</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n Akorne-cups fill'd to the brinke.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:12422:10"/>
               <l>The tongues of Nightingales,</l>
               <l>With unctious iuyce of Snailes,</l>
               <l>Betwixt two nut-ſhels ſtewde</l>
               <l>Is meat thats eaſily chewde:</l>
               <l>The braines of Rrnnes, the beards of mice</l>
               <l>Will make a feaſt of wondrous price.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Over the tender graſſe,</l>
               <l>So lightly we can paſſe,</l>
               <l>The yong and tender ſtalke,</l>
               <l>Nere bowes whereon we walke,</l>
               <l>Nor in the morning dew is ſeene,</l>
               <l>Over night where we have béene.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The graſſe-hopper, gnat, and flie,</l>
               <l>Serves for our Minſtrels thrée,</l>
               <l>And ſweetly dance a while,</l>
               <l>Till we the time beguile:</l>
               <l>And when the Moone-calfe hides her head.</l>
               <l>The glow-worme lights us unto bed.</l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="illustration">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:11"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>depiction of Adam and Eve cast out of Paradise</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="song">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:11"/>
            <head>The Melancholly Lovers Song.</head>
            <l>HEnce all you vaine delights,</l>
            <l>As ſhort as are the nights</l>
            <l>Wherein you ſpend your folly,</l>
            <l>There's nought in this life ſweet,</l>
            <l>If men were wiſe to ſee't,</l>
            <l>But onely melancholly.</l>
            <l>Welcome folded hands, and fixed eyes,</l>
            <l>A ſigh thats piercing, mortifies,</l>
            <l>A looke that's faſtned on the ground,</l>
            <l>A tongue chained up without a ſound:</l>
            <l>Fountaine heads, and pathleſſe groves,</l>
            <l>Are places where pale paſſion loves.</l>
            <l>Moone-light walkes, when all the fowles</l>
            <l>Are warmely hous'd, ſave Bats and owles;</l>
            <l>A midnight bell, a parting grone,</l>
            <l>Theſe are the ſighes I feed upon:</l>
            <l>Then ſtretcht out bones in a ſtill gloomy valley</l>
            <l>There's nothing dainty, ſweet to melancholly</l>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="illustration">
            <pb facs="tcp:12422:12"/>
            <p>
               <figure/>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
